Alright, here we go again. It looks like Charles has a bit of a hot take on a beloved new film that just came out 31 year old man
Still has to go against the green the old-fashioned way
But I can't help it. I'm a little sea turtle fight fight in the tide here. Go in the other direction on it a little bit
Weapons debuted at a hundred percent on Rotten Tomatoes people hyping and glazing it out the wazoo about it being like the best horror movie ever
Which I think is more of a curse than a blessing. It reminds me of long legs
How like a core component of its marketing was hope you brought your diaper because you're pissing in it with how scary
This one is you're gonna be sucking on your thumb till you pop that bitch right off your hand. It's too scary
What are we doing? We shouldn't even release movies this scary and then I saw long legs and it was just fine and
With weapons the hype is not quite to that level
But you know 100% Ron tomatoes people of course going ballistic for it with how incredible it is
I've never seen a horror movie like this. I've just seen it
Kind of feel the same way that about long legs like it's fine like I enjoyed it. I had a good time
But man oh man is it not nearly to the level that a lot of people are portraying it as at least not in my eyes
Not that I let the hype really skew my thoughts on things
I just thought I was worth mentioning that to me this film isn't what people are
Gassing it up as it's a horror movie sure
But I would actually argue it's more of a comedy like and I don't think people are aware of that
I don't we're gonna get into spoilers of course. I do spoilers now when reviewing things
So this is your warning there. I would say there's actually more comedic elements to this film than there are horror elements
Like the actual plot and a lot of the things that happen very clearly supposed to give you the heebie-jeebies
But all of it is undercut with comedy and humor even in the most tense situations. It's like the MCU of horror
So like you'll have something that is clearly like wow
This is going to be like scary. Oh my god. We have built up to this huge tense moment
And then they play it off as a joke especially at the end of the movie. I'm gonna get to that here in a little bit and
It was fine like I don't hate that but it's not really a horror when it's not taking itself seriously
You know what I mean? Anyway, I really like this director Zach Kregger
He of course I like this work in NYS could you know, but he really surprised me with barbarian
Barbarian is a film I saw on a whim and I was blown away by with how interesting it was and just how much I ended up really enjoying it
So like I was very hyped to see this as well and I do like it
I just didn't love it like I was hoping I would and I think a lot of people are expecting this to be one thing
When it's really not that thing like I think they're going to get something completely different than what they're expecting and for some people
That might be nice for others. It might be a bit of a let down in my theater in particular
This isn't just me being like big tough macho man. No movie scare Charlie
He too strong for movie to make him scared. I mean like this is actually like I'm pretty sure by design supposed to make you laugh
Everyone in my theater was laughing a lot in this movie more so than there were like any kind of like on edge
Stripes from people nobody like gasp or anything
It really felt like most people were there having a hoot and a holler at it
And I think it's not laughing at the film. It's with it
Like I said it feels like it's supposed to be more of like this
Unserious take on a horror movie
When everyone else seems to be talking about it as just like a full blown horror film
So I want to kind of set the record straight on that anyway the film has a really interesting premise everyone's talked about that a lot
It's about this town where for some reason
mysteriously at 217 a.m
An entire classroom of kids all gets up in the middle of the night goes downstairs walks out the front door and disappears into the night
They run away and they run away with their arms at their side. It's really weird
They're running like the Titans from attack on Titan a month goes by they still have no leads can't figure it out
Of course the parents are distraught the town still trying to you know recover from this because everyone's on edge about it and
And
Now we follow the court characters one being the teacher of that classroom where all the students except for one disappeared
We then follow some other characters like one of the parents and it's a really interesting way of telling the story because you go through
Some scenes multiple times from other characters perspectives which fill in a lot of the blanks
And I thought it was really creative. I thought it was very fun
It actually reminded me of something like out of a video game like almost until dawn asked to a certain extent
Like I thought that was a really cool idea to visit these things from a different characters eyes like chapters in this movie
I thought that worked extraordinarily well because you get so many different pieces of this puzzle through so many different lenses that all of course
Meet at the end everything comes together and I just thought that was really smart
I also really liked the way the movies filmed
I've seen a lot of like people praising the cinematography going into this film
And I think it definitely deserves that it is like a really well shot movie
They have some really creative scenes that are shot in a really interesting manner
It's not all just like the standard by the book formula that horror movies follow or I guess comedies by that extension
I thought they got very creative with their shots. It's clear they were having a lot of fun
The performances across the board
I thought were super strong as well, especially with justine
She's the teacher of that classroom where all the students
Vanished at 217 a.m. where they all ran away in the whole town hates her
They torment her. She's ostracized. They think she had something to do with it is withholding information
maybe even just she you know mastermind the whole thing and then you start getting these questions in your head about
Well, where is this going to go?
And then you go to the next chapter and you'll see a character that initially you don't really see how that ties in anywhere and
Then all of a sudden bang Eureka. This is where it's leading but
This is one of my big holdups with the film
The questions that you have the answers the movie gives you aren't all that
Interesting like the questions themselves and the premise of the film are so strong like the mystery of it
The thrill of trying to solve it trying to see where it all leads and then when you get to where it leads
It's a little
Unfulfilling like I feel like it's just a little underwhelming especially because the final act as I mentioned earlier is
Played off as a joke
That kind of takes a lot of wind out of the sales you spend the whole movie with this mystery in these questions
only to then meet the
big scary entity
Which is just an old sick lady with a magic tree and she has badly put on makeup with this
wacky zany wig. It's like a Ronald McDonald's wig
It looks like Chuck E. Finster if he went to the worst barber on the east coast and she like jump scares you occasionally throughout the film
And that's like the main horror as they rely on her being like the jump scare moment
It's like Josh Brolin when he's looking for his kid he goes into like the dream space like he's in a nightmare chasing his son Matthew
And as he's telling his son Matthew
I know I never said I love you enough
But I really do love you son then all of a sudden he looks at his son's face
And it's that old lady her name is Gladys and she's like
And like
She does that a couple times. She's like the thing bringing horror to the movie because
Without her doing that sometimes. It's just not really present
Like I said, it really is more of like a dark comedy kind of film as opposed to like a horror film
Not to like split hairs
But then as you have all these questions that you spend like an hour and a half you know stewing on trying to piece it together
And you go through a bunch of different characters perspectives
then
One character meets Gladys and then all the answers start coming in
Gladys is the big bad and it's just kind of underwhelming
Because from that point forward a lot of what Gladys does gets played off
Comedically
Unfortunately, but it's not just her every time there is like a horror sequence playing out
They undercut it with humor
So for example justine is spying on a house
Where she believes there might be something fishy afoot and then she falls asleep in her car
And while she's passed out the door opens and a lady comes out and she's holding scissors and she's walking weird
She's walking real weird and she's like she's literally walking like doodle bob actually and she gets to the car
She's right by the window and then she's just like kind of walks away like crab walks away
The theater laughed really hard when that happened and then the backseat open or the back door opens
And you can hear her get into the car and then it's like tense
It's like oh, okay, this is like a good tense moment
And then she leans over and cuts some hair and then the theater laughed again
So like they took a horror moment
Made it silly then brought some kind of like horror life into it where it's like oh
This is about to be like kind of intense like what's about to happen and then played a joke again on it
So you know what I mean like you know, I'm trying to say it's like
It does have horror and when it's there it's executed pretty well
Like I think there's like some solid scenes
But they always take the wind out of the sales of the horror aspect in order to play a joke into it
Now granted the joke is solid too like it was clearly landing with the audience
But I feel like a lot of people might find that to be annoying or not what they signed up for
For me, I didn't care that much like it. I thought it was fine
Definitely different for sure and I was still entertained
Especially because in the last act they don't even try to make it scary
They literally play it as like almost a slapstick comedy
Skit in the end they pieced together the mystery which by the way the way they figured out where the kids were
To me felt like they kind of wrote themselves into a corner and then couldn't figure out like a good way of getting there
Basically they were able to connect the dots like the pose that they were running in and after another guy goes crazy while doing that pose
They then the Josh Brolin's character tracked the trajectory and then justine was like
Oh, that's the house of like that one lone survivor kid like the one kid that didn't run away
Probably something about that house and it's a house she previously visited like with the scissors and shit
So they figured it out because of the pose but
The authorities like scrubbed over this footage a lot and there's even this montage sequence
They showed where all the kids were running in a group together in front of houses
Literally triggering motion sensor lights and everything they were running in groups to this house
I feel like the ring doorbells would have absolutely caught them running in groups
And they probably would have been able to find them far far sooner
I don't know how they would have missed that
Like they made a mention like the ring doorbells only caught them like running into the night
But they passed so many houses in groups like I feel like that footage would have absolutely existed
They could have easily tracked that trajectory like I don't think it would just be Josh Brolin
That would somehow figure out like it's kind of weird that they're all doing the same pose
Maybe they were running somewhere
Especially when you would couple that with these groups of kids that no doubt would have been caught on all these cameras from all of these houses that they're running in front of
And triggering all the motion detection
Like I don't know
But anyway they find the house they go to the house
And they're like in the house and she can control people with her magic tree
So she has like bodyguards of people that she's controlled
That's how she got the kids because she mind controlled them to you know go hang out in the basement
And while they're there trying to save these kids
Two people that she's controlled one of them being a junkie start attacking justine and Josh Brolin
I don't know why I keep calling I don't know why I'm calling Julia Gardner's character by her character name and Josh Brolin
Instead of his character name calling him Josh Brolin, but whatever
They're there and they get of course ganked by her bodyguards that she's controlling and I shit you not one of the bodyguards
Josh Brolin punches and he gets knocked out and then he gets up again
He punches and he goes geez what the hell he gets knocked out the guy gets up again punches him again
knocks him out and by this point the theater is like actually erupting in the laughter
And then his Josh Brolin's running away guy gets up again charges him and he picks him up and actually ragdolls him
And then he's like god, he's so persistent
And then he's walking away and the guy gets up again screaming and shouting running at him and he ragdolls him again
Literally like WWE like the fucking soup flexing him and throwing him around
And then theater is literally laughing at all this when this is like the entire buildup that we have built up to this
Moment and it is like actually just a slapstick routine
It just feels underwhelming like it's I still think it's fun like I mean laughing at a movie is great
But if you're going there expecting horror like a really good horror movie
I don't think that's what you're in the store for and it's not just that scene
It's this entire sequence the finale of all of this tension this buildup all of your questions
Being answered but the answer just not really all that amazing so like the
Gladys she's about to have justine killed and
Alex the one kid who did not get mind controlled by Gladys and the magic tree
He was watching Gladys understands how to like control the magic tree and use its branches
So he frees the kids well not freeze the kids
He uses the the reason the movie is called weapons is because Gladys weaponizes people
She's able to control them and have them do whatever she wants
So Alex then uses the kids as weapons against Gladys where they then chase her down hunter and kill her
And this is a I shit you not like
Maybe eight to nine minute chase sequence of Gladys going oh no
She literally says oh no when the branch breaks when he when he breaks the spell and like directs the kids at her
She literally says oh no and then starts doing this
Opens the door running away as all the kids are chasing the her going
And she's going ah
So she's running away getting chased by the kids and then she starts like breaking into strangers houses
And they played off as a joke so like there's a family like watching TV and then they'll you know Gladys comes through and they're like oh my goodness
And she's like
And she runs through kitchen runs out the front door and like that was weird and then all the kids bus through the windows
A bus through the door like oh Jesus Christ and they do that for like three separate houses
There's one where guys mowing his lawn sees Gladys running away going ah
He's like huh and then the horde of kids starts chasing him and he's like
Huh
Like they play it has a joke you know what I mean like I think it's an effective comedy movie
But overall I just felt like it was a fun movie it was it was good
It wasn't like amazing
I definitely don't think it's the horror movie of the decade or anything and all things like I don't even think it's the horror movie of the year
I still think bring her back is a significantly better like horror film
But I think this was solid with the horror that was here
sprinkled throughout occasionally
And I think the comedy was solid which is here in a bigger capacity than the horror like it's it's to me
It's more of like almost a dark comedy kind of and I think maybe that was the goal
I didn't know that going into it based on the trailers and what people are saying about it
But after seeing it I would definitely classify this more as like a dark comedy as opposed to some kind of like horror film
But I do think you will walk away entertained. I know I was but yeah
I just have to disagree with the hype a little bit on this one here sports fans. Sorry to tell you
But it's not like I was super disappointed or anything. It was still a fun time. It's really about it. See you